Guide to the Lynne Huffer papers on Benefits Equality at Rice University, 1997 - 2004 MS 595
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Lynne Huffer papers on Benefits Equality at Rice University
1997 - 2004
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Huffer, Lynne
MS 595
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
This collection consists of non-academic papers of Dr. Lynne Huffer that reflect her university community activities while she was on the faculty at Rice from 1998 to 2005. Among these activities are work on a campaign to extend university benefits coverage to domestic partners; protesting against a publicly quoted homophobic statement made by head football coach Ken Hatfield; surveying the Rice campus climate, particularly regarding women; serving on the President's Council on the Campus Climate for Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender individuals; and working on the 2003-2004 ad hoc committee for on-site child care at Rice.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Lynne Huffer became a member of the Rice University French Department and Director of the Program for the Study of Women and Gender in August 1998. She served in these roles until May 2005, when she left Rice to join the faculty at Emory University. Becoming active in faculty work on university governance, she was elected deputy speaker of the Faculty Senate in 2003-04 and speaker in 2004-05. Her committee work included a campaign to persuade the university administration to make benefits available to domestic partners of faculty and staff, as well as to their family members; a faculty response to a publicly quoted homophobic statement made by head football coach Ken Hatfield; a study of the Rice campus climate, particularly regarding women; serving on President Gillis's Council on the Campus Climate for Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender individuals; and participation on an ad hoc committee to bring about on-site childcare at Rice.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of non-academic papers of Dr. Lynne Huffer that reflect her committee activities while she was at Rice from 1998 to 2005. Appointed as a member of the French Department and Director of the Program for the Study of Women and Gender, she was active on several committees formed to improve working conditions or the quality of campus life at Rice. The first of these was an ultimately successful campaign to persuade the university administration to allow benefit coverage for domestic partners of employees as well as employees and their families. Also included are papers relating to campus turmoil surrounding head football coach Ken Hatfield, following a homophobic statement he made to one of his student players which was quoted in The Chronicle of Higher Education as well as the local press. The papers include results of a survey on the campus climate at Rice, especially regarding women, as well as records of Dr. Huffer's participation when President Gillis asked her to be on the President's Council on the Campus Climate for Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender individuals. Finally are papers recording the work of the 2003-04 ad hoc committee for on-site childcare at Rice.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Lynne Huffer Papers, MS 595, Woodson Research Center, Fondren Library, Rice University.
Index Terms
Subjects
LGBTQ people; Rice University -- History; Universities and colleges; Women
Document Types
letters (correspondence); notes
- Series I: Benefits Research, 0.75 Linear Feet
  - Domestic Partner Benefits 1997-98 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Domestic Partner Benefits 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Information gathered about Domestic Partner Benefits at other institutions (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Published articles about Domestic Partner Benefits (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Material gathered by Paula Sanders during campaign for Domestic Partner Benefits (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Material gathered by Dan Sherman during campaign for Domestic Partner Benefits (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Survey, Report, and Materials about Campus Climate at Rice, especially for Women (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Coach Hatfield, homophobic comment case – Nov. 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - President's Council on GLBT Campus Climate – 2002- (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - On-site Childcare for Rice – ad hoc committee – 2003-04 (Box 1, Folder 10)